# **Andre Rogers**

andrejprogers@gmail.com http://andrerogers.github.io/ California +1 630-974-8533

An accomplished **Software Engineer** specializing in **Object Oriented Design** and **Analysis** having experience in the full life cycle of the software development process including *requirements definition*, *prototyping*, *proof of concept, design, interface implementation, testing and maintenance* with the ability to learn new skills and project details quickly, find creative solutions to challenging problems.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

### Freelance, Full Stack Programmer (May 2016 – May 2017)

- Gathered specs and requirements from client to accurately build a workflow.
- Used Semantic HTML and the CSS Box Model for describing the structure and style.
- Used **Angular** for front end scripting and **Node.js** for the backend.
- Interacted with and created a relational database, using TSQL, SQL Server.
- Wrote use cases and performed UAT (User Acceptance Testing) while using Jira to track bugs.
- Used the MEAN stack i.e. Mongo, Express, Angular and Node.js to create a RESTful API to connect with CoinKite for CRUD operations as a proof of concept to create a Bit Coin wallet.

## Governor State University, Media Technology Assistant (April 2016 – March 2017)

- Encapsulated teaching material such as videos, lecture notes and other related course material into a single package using Lectora, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript for offline digital distribution.
- Conducted meetings with teachers and faculty to gather and compile requirements.

#### Freelance, Web Developer Consultant (July 2014 - May 2015)

- Refactored code for optimization purposed and better readability.
- Modified the database to optimize its design for quicker response times, by normalization.
- Created responsive webpages to react responsively to change in screen size or resolution.
- Wrote webpages for a website hosted on a Joomla CMS (Content Management System) using JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, and PHP.

#### Dhruva Interactive, Game Programmer (June 2013 - June 2014)

- Developed games for the **iOS** and **Android** platforms.
- Built a 3D model loader in the Unity Engine to render with physically based shaders.
- Contributed to the code base in terms of gameplay, physics and rendering using C#.
- Worked with QA, to **design test cases** to verify code, and mechanics.
- Performed regression testing to check efficiency of algorithms when they were changed.
- Active participant in scrums and contributed retroactively during sprint retrospectives.

## **EDUCATION:**

- Governors State University, University Park, IL (Graduate August 2016) Master of Science in Computer Science
- Trinity College Dublin, Ireland (Graduated August 2012) Post Graduate Diploma Computer Science Interactive Entertainment Technology (Game Development)
- St. Joseph's College of Arts and Science, Karnataka, India (Graduated May 2011) Bachelor of Computer Applications

## TECHNICAL SKILLS:

- Languages C, C++, C#, HTML5, JavaScript, CSS3, ASP .NET, SQL, AngularJS, Node.js, Express, MongoDB
- API's / Frameworks OpenGL, GLSL
- Tools / Applications Visual Studio, VS Code, SQL Server, SQL Management Studio, Unity, Unreal Engine 4, Git